# **Sayeed Nabil Hossain**

Mohammodpur, Panchlaish, Chattogram, Bangladesh

Mobile : +880 1821429162

Email: nabilhossain905@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nabil-hossain-65b7b2190

Wechat : nabilnuaa

### **Career Objective:**

Fresh graduate specializing in CAD/CAM software, Blender.A focused and devoted individual with excellent time management skills and design abilities searching for a position in a fast-paced environment that will allow me to use my knowledge and experience in assisting company production processes.

### **Educational Qualification:**

Honor's (B.Eng.)

Institution : Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics 2018-2022(July)

29 Yudao St., Nanjing, Jiangsu, China

Department: Mechanical Engineering (Final year 8<sup>th</sup> semester)

GPA : 2.90 (79%, Up to 7<sup>th</sup> semester)

Thesis Defense completed, waiting for the result.

### **Experiences:**

→ Fineline Interiors (180,Shantibagh,Dhaka)

**2021(March)-2022(January)** 

#### Office Associate

My responsibility was to:

- o Provide administrative and clerical support to office staff to run office efficiently.
- o Perform word processing of records and prepare necessary reports and other documents.



- Manage and enter data to existing databases, spreadsheets and generate required reports on demand.
- Monitor and process all records, forms and various other documents as per existing procedures and policies.
- Maintain reports, records and various other documents for sorting and bind them for documentation, administer all bookkeeping activities, post accounting data and compare invoices with purchase orders to check accuracy.
- Perform research and compile information for reports, forms, records and other similar documentation.

#### **♦ CAD/CAM workshop, NUAA**

2020

#### **Trainer**

A workshop that was set by the CIECG (NUAA international student center group) to train students basics of cad/cam software. I was a trainer to teach the participants how to design in Solidworks 3D CAD design software and help them whenever they need.

### **♦** Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics

Dec 2019- Jan 2020

#### Lab assistant, CAD/CAM lab

Worked under Professor Lu-min (assistant professor, department of mechanical engineering, NUAA) as a Lab assistant for 2019 undergraduate freshmen in their "Engineering Graphics "course. My responsibility was to help the new students at the lab to finish their Solid works (CAD/CAM) projects.

#### **♦** Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics

Dec 2019- Jan 2020

#### **Engineering Training**

Learned to operate CNC Mining, CNC Turning, Lathe Machine, Wire EDM and Laser beam machining

#### **Projects:**

Name: Single-stage cylindrical gear reducer for belt conveyor

2020

**Objective**: I had to design a belt conveyor in Autocad and Solidworks that includes a gear reducer, shaft, and some other parts like bearings, key, coupling, housing, etc. The goal was to

design a belt conveyor that has:

Steady load

Unidirectional transmission

o Tolerance of transmission ratio of v-belt drive and gear drive: ≤±5%

o Daily working hour: 24

o Working days per year: 250

o Service life of the driving system: 5 years

o Design life of bearings: >10000 hrs

Name: Multi-defect interaction simulation and analysis using Finite Element Method (FEM)

Ongoing final year thesis research project.

### **Extra-Curricular Activities:**

**Nuaa Aircraft Modeling Competition** 

2018

**Participant** 

NUAA College of international education center group (CIECG)

Jan 2019-Jan 2020

General Member, Study and Living Department

The College of international education center group (CIECG) is the central organization for the international students of Nanjing University of Aeronautics and Astronautics working under the direct supervision of College of international education for the general welfare of students and smooth running of college activities.

#### China Mountain Bike Competition (MTB, International Group)

Weihei, Shandong, China

2020

**Participant** 

### **Skills:**

- o Vast Knowledge in Autodesk Inventor, Catia, Fusion 360, and Blender.
- o Experienced and highly skilled in **Solidworks** & **Abaqus FEA CAE** software.
- o Proficient in Microsoft Office.

#### **Language proficiency**:

- o Bangla (Native)
- o English (Fluent)
- Chinese (Proficient)
- German (Proficient)

### **Achievements:**

- ♦ NUAA outstanding result scholarship -3rd prize. (2019-2020)

### **References:**

Mohammed Rokibul Hossain Eng.Md. Showket Asgar

Assistant manager commercial Proprietor

Email: **Showket.asgar@yahoo.com** Email: **Showket.asgar@yahoo.com** 

Contact: +880 1717193012 Contact: 01712224831

Biman Bangladesh Airlines Fineline Interiors

Kurmitola, Dhaka-1229, Bangladesh 180, Shantibagh, Dhaka-12

## **Personal Information:**

Father's Name : S.M Jashim Uddin

Mother's Name : Syeda Nasima Akter

Date of Birth : 28<sup>th</sup> August, 1999

Permanent Address : 257/A,Mohammodpur,Panchlaish,Chattogram,Bangladesh

Religion : Islam

Nationality : Bangladeshi

NID : 7815157461

Marital Status : Single

Blood Group : B(+)

Sayeed Nabil Hossain

Signature